I'm glad you're here.
（サテラ）
よかった いてくれて
今度は逃がさないから
You won't get away this time.
Why's she here?
（ナツキ･スバル）
どうしてあの子がここに？
まだ明るい時間なのに
It's still light out.
Wait, would she have arrived
this early if I wasn't with her?
ひょっとして 俺がいなけりゃ―
こんだけ早く―
たどり着けたって
ことか？
You never quit, do you?
（フェルト）
ほんとしつこい女だな
あんた
Why don't you just give up already!?
いいかげん諦めろっつうのに！
Sorry, but this isn't something I can give up on.
残念だけど
諦められない物だから
Surrender quietly and I won't hurt you.
おとなしくすれば
痛い思いはさせないわ
I have only one demand:
私からの要求は１つ―
return my insignia.
徽章(きしょう)を返して
It's very important to me.
あれは 大切な物なの
I wouldn't back down if she were just
another magic user, but this one's trouble.
（ロム爺(じい)）
ただの魔法使い相手なら
わしも引いたりせんが―
この相手はマズい
What's with you, Old Man Rom?
何だよ ロム爺 ケンカやる前から
負け認めんのか？
You're throwing in the towel before we even fight?
Little miss, you're an elf, ain't ya?
お嬢ちゃん あんた エルフじゃろ
Not exactly.
正しくは違う
私がエルフなのは 半分だけだから
I'm only a half-elf.
A half-elf?
ハーフエルフ？
それも銀髪？ まさか…
With silver hair? Wait, are you...
I just happen to look like her!
他人の空似よ
私だって迷惑してるもの
And it causes me nothing but trouble.
兄ちゃん さてはまんまと
私をはめたな？
You set me up, didn't you?
Huh? No, I didn't do anything.
（スバル）
はあ？ いや 俺はなにも…
I knew something was up when you said you'd return it to its owner!
持ち主に返すとか
おかしなこと 言いやがるから―
怪しいとは思ってたんだ！
What do you mean?
どういうこと？ あなたたち
仲間なんじゃないの？
Aren't you two working together?
She never changes, no matter
how many times I start over.
（スバル）
この子の心根は
世界を何度繰り返しても
変わってない
Hey! What are you laughing about!?
（フェルト）
何だよてめえ 何 笑ってんだ！
Come on, the jig's up.
Just return her insignia.
まあまあ いいじゃねえか
フェルトは徽章を返してやれよ
And Sat—
そんで サ… 君は
早くここから出てく
I mean, you hurry up and get out of here.
Try not to let anyone steal it again.
もう盗られたりしないようにな
Why are you being so nice all of a sudden?
何で 急に親身に
なってくれてるの？
I don't understand at all.
私 すごーく
釈然としないんだけど
I'm with her! Try making some sense for once!
（フェルト）
納得いかねえのは
私も一緒だよ 兄ちゃん
What's with you!?
あんた 何なんだよ！
Puck! Shield her!
パック 防げ！
I blocked that by the skin of my teeth.
（パック）
なかなかどうして
紙一重のタイミングだったね
Thanks for the warning!
助かったよ
Nice one, Puck!
ナイス パック
We're so lucky that you're on the clock until five!
まだ５時前
勤務時間内で助かった
あんがとよ
Thanks!
A spirit...
（エルザ･グランヒルテ）
精霊　精霊ね
That is a spirit, yes?
ウフフ ステキ
How wonderful.
I've never split open a spirit's stomach before.
精霊は まだ
お腹を割ってみたことないから
ウフ
Hey, what's the big idea here?
おい どういうことだよ
We can hardly negotiate
if the item's original owner is here.
持ち主までもってこられては
商談なんて とてもとても
So there's been a slight change of plan.
だから予定を変更したのよ
I shall slaughter everyone here.
この場にいる関係者は皆殺し
You failed to see your job through to the end.
あなたは仕事を全うできなかった
You talk a good game,
but you do terrible work.
口ばかり達者なだけで
お粗末な仕事ぶり―
You really are just another slum dweller.
所詮は 貧民街の人間ね
（スバル）てめえ
You bitch...
Cut the crap!
ふざけんなよ！
こんな小さいガキいじめて
楽しんでんじゃねえよ！
Don't get your kicks from picking on a little kid!
You guts-loving sadist!
腸(はらわた)大好きのサディステック女が！
Felt is doing her best to live strong!
フェルトだって
精一杯 強く生きてんだよ
And here you are flipping tables just
because your plan was thrown off a bit!
予定狂ったから
ちゃぶ台ひっくり返して―
全部オジャンって ガキか てめえは
命を大事にしろ！
Who's the little kid here!?
You should value life more!
Do you know how much it hurts
to have your belly sliced open!?
腹 斬られると
どんだけ痛いか知ってんのか？
Well, I do!
俺は知ってます！
What are you talking about?
何を言ってるの？ あなた
I'm letting the sense of justice and chivalry
I never knew I had denounce the world's unfairness!
（スバル）
自分の中の思わぬ正義感と
義きょう心に任せて―
この世の理不尽を弾劾中だよ
俺にとっての理不尽は
つまり お前で この状況で―
And what I consider "unfair" is you,
this entire situation, and...
Stay tuned, folks.
チャンネルは そのままでどうぞ
There!
はい
All done buying time.
時間稼ぎ終了
Get her, Puck!
やっちまえー パック
A cringeworthy performance
that I hope is remembered for generations.
後世に残したい
見事な無様(ぶざま)さだったね
I'd better not let you down!
期待に応えようぞ
I haven't introduced myself yet, have I?
まだ 自己紹介もしてなかったね
お嬢さん
My name's Puck.
僕の名前はパック
Take my name with you...
名前だけでも覚えていってね
to your grave!
Did they get 'er!?
やりおったか？
Don't trigger that flag, old man!
そのフラグ立てんな ジジイ
One should always be prepared for anything.
（エルザ）
備えはしておくものね
You can't beat a spirit arts user that easily.
精霊術の使い手をナメないこと
戦い慣れしてるなあ 女の子なのに
You're pretty used to battle for a girl.
（エルザ）
あら 女の子扱いされるなんて
随分と久しぶりなのだけれど
My, it's been a while since
I was regarded as a simple girl.
Well, from my perspective,
all opponents are basically babies.
（パック）
僕から見れば 大抵の相手は
赤ん坊みたいなものだからね
Still, you're so strong, I almost pity you.
それにしても ふびんなくらい
強いもんだね 君は
I'm deeply touched to be praised by a spirit.
（エルザ）
精霊に褒められるなんて
恐れ多いことだわ
I think we'll come out on top
if it boils down to attrition.
このまま消耗戦に持ち込めば
なんとか勝てんじゃねえか？
No, fer a spirit, the real battle is how long they can keep themselves 'ere.
いいや 精霊がいつまで
顕現できるかが勝負じゃ
うっ そろそろ５時を回るか
That's right! It's almost five.
Oh, and just when we were
having such fun. What a bore.
あら せっかく楽しみに
なってきたのにつれないわ
That's what sucks about being a ladies' man.
モテるオスのつらいところだね
The girls just won't let you sleep.
女の子のほうが
寝かせてくれないんだから
But you know, staying up late is bad
for your skin, so we should wrap this up!
でも ほら 夜更かしすると
お肌に悪いから―
そろそろ幕引きといこうか
I wasn't just randomly littering those around.
無目的にばらまいていたわけじゃ
にゃいんだよ
Oh, have I been played?
してやられたってことかしら
Sleep tight!
おやすみ
My, how lovely...
（エルザ）ああ ステキ
死んじゃうかと思ったわ
I thought I was going to die.
I don't find that kind of
trait attractive in a girl.
女の子なんだから そういうのは
僕 感心しないなあ
Puck, can you keep going?
パック まだいける？
Sorry, I'm really sleepy.
ごめん すごい眠い
ちょっとナメてかかってた
I underestimated her a bit.
I don't have the mana to stay any longer.
マナ切れで消えちゃう
I'll take care of things here, so you can rest.
あとは こっちでどうにかするから
今は休んで
Thank you.
ありがとね
君に何かあれば
僕は 契約に従う
If anything happens to you,
I'll abide by my contract.
Call me, even if it means forcing me out with your odo, if you really have to.
いざとなったら―
オドを絞り出してでも
僕を呼び出すんだよ
You're leaving?
（エルザ）
いなくなってしまうの？
Well, that is very unfortunate.
それはひどく残念なことだわ
そろそろ ただ見てるだけという
わけにはいかんの フェルト
We can't keep just sitting around an' watchin', Felt.
Yeah, I know.
分かってるっつうの
If you're gonna run, now's the time.
逃げるにせよ―
そろそろ 動かねえと
いけねえってな
And about before...
さっきは なんだ―
I guess you kinda saved me.
ちょっと 救われた
Just a little, though.
ちょっとだけ だけどな
Oh, right! Don't call me a little kid!
つか ガキとか言うんじゃねえよ
私はこれでも15だ
I'm fifteen, you know!
兄ちゃんとほとんど
変わんねえだろ
That can't be much younger than you!
I'm eighteen this year.
俺は今年で18だ
え… 見えねえ ガキすぎ
No way! You look like a little brat!
Life's been way too easy on you!
もうちょっと
人生刻んどけよ ツラに
Here I come!
（ロム爺）行くぞー！
Oh, my. Isn't it a bit boorish
to cut in on a dance?
あら ダンスに横入りなんて
不粋じゃないかしら？
If you wanna dance, I'll show you
the best dancin' you've ever seen!
（ロム爺）
そんなに踊りたければ
最高のダンスを踊らせてやる
そら きりきり舞え！
Here we go! Round an' round!
What in the—
なんじゃそらー？
フッ あなたが力持ちだから
こんなこともできたのよ
You're so strong that I can do something like this!
Not gonna happen!
（フェルト）させっか！
Old Man Rom!
ロム爺ー！
You bad girl.
（エルザ）悪い子
覚悟も戦う力もない
You have neither the resolve nor strength to fight.
You should have just stayed in the corner
and made yourself small.
ならば せめて部屋の隅で
小さくなっているべきだったのに
Damn, we're done for.
This is totally hopeless.
（スバル）
クソ ダメだ
やっぱどうしようもねえ
I guess I'll have to trigger
Return by Death and try again.
こうなりゃ もう１回
死に戻ってやり直すか
No, I really don't want to
go through that pain again.
いや もうあんな苦しい思いは
したくねえ
I don't wanna die!
死にたくねえ
I guess as long as I'm still kicking
結局は 生あるかぎりは
精一杯あがくしかないってことか
all I can do is fight with all my might.
Haidara!
Are you okay?
大丈夫か？
Why did you...
つか どうして…
Listen to me, Felt. I'm going to buy us time.
よく聞け　いいか フェルト
俺が今から時間を稼ぐ
I'll give you an opening somehow.
So when I do, run as fast as you can!
どうにか隙を作ってみせっから
その間に お前は全力で逃げろ
What? You're telling me to tuck
my tail between my legs and run!?
何だそりゃ 私に
ケツまくって逃げろってのか？
Exactly! Stick out your butt,
tuck in your tail, and run!
そうだ ケツまくって
尻尾巻いて逃げちまえ
You're fifteen, and I'm eighteen.
お前は15で 俺は18
That means you're probably
the youngest one here.
たぶん お前がこの中で
一番年下ってことになる
It's obvious we'd pick whatever has
the highest chance of keeping you alive!
そしたら お前が生きる確率が
一番高いとこ選ぶのは当たり前だ
Totally obvious!
当たり前なんだよ
Give me a break. You were cowering
in fear just a minute ago!
何だよそれ！
ふざけんな さっきまで
ブルッてたくせに
That was then. This is now.
さっきはさっき 今は今
All that matters is I'm not now.
今 ブルッてねえから
それでよし！
Take this!
（スバル）だらーっ！
今だ 行けよフェルト！
Now! Go, Felt!
Do you think I'll let her go?
行かせると思う？
Whoa, I'm awesome!
俺 すげえ
But that hurt my toes more than I expected.
でも 思いのほか
つま先がイッテー…
How about that? You let someone get away.
まんまと １人逃がしたったぜ
It did arouse a rare sense of irritation.
（エルザ）
珍しく 少しだけ
腹立たしいと思ったわ
Don't forget about me.
（サテラ）
こっちの相手も忘れないでよね
I've grown quite tired of that game already.
そのお遊びも
そろそろ見飽きたのだけれど―
まだ私を楽しませられそう？
Do you think you can still entertain me?
If you've been holding anything back,
秘められた真の力とかが
あるなら―
now would be a good time to use it.
今のうちに出しといたほうが
いいと思うぜ
I do have a trump card.
（サテラ）
切り札はあるけど―
But I'd be the only one left standing if I used it.
使うと 私以外は
誰も残らないわよ
No self-destructing, please.
自爆は勘弁
お願いだから早まらないでね
Don't do anything hasty, okay?
I won't use it.
使ったりしないわよ
Not while you're still here...
まだ一生懸命 あなたが…
trying your hardest.
頑張ってるのに
Nothing happened just now.
（スバル）
今 俺は何も見なかった
Huh?
That whole conversation never happened!
（スバル）
今のやりとりは
全部無しだ 全部無し
I finally remembered why I'm here in the first place.
何で俺がここにいるのか
やっと思い出した
I'll kill you, shitbag!
やってやるぜ クソダラ！
I won't let that trump card be played!
切り札なんざ
ぜってえ切らせねえ
I'll blow you away and get
てめえ ぶっ飛ばして―
a happy ending!
ハッピーエンドだ
It looks like you have a bit too much energy.
元気が有り余ってるようね
You black widow!
（スバル）クモ女か！
It is certainly true that you are caught in my web.
（エルザ）
あなたは先にからめとられるのは
間違いないのだけれど
Nice cover!
（スバル）ナイスカバー
Damn it!
How do you like this!?
これなら どうだ…
I caught you.
はい つかんだ
（スバル）うっ
（エルザ）ウフ
That's enough.
（男）そこまでだ
（男）
危ないところだったようだけど
間に合ってなによりだ
It looks like I cut it close,
but I'm glad I made it in time.
Now...
さあ…
You're...
あなたは
Shall we put an end to this?
（ラインハルト･ヴァン･
アストレア）
舞台の幕を引くとしようか
（フェルト）誰か！
Someone!
誰か 誰かいないのかよ！
Anyone!
Come on, there has to be someone!
Damn it!
チクショウ
Please... Please, someone...
お願い お願い
誰か… 誰か助けて！
Someone help!
（ラインハルト）分かった
Very well.
I shall help you.
助けるよ
Reinhard?
ラインハルト… か？
Indeed, Subaru.
（ラインハルト）
そうだよ スバル　さっきぶりだね
We meet again. Sorry I'm late.
遅れてすまない
Black hair, black clothes,
黒髪に黒い装束
そして 北国特有の刀剣
and a blade unique to the northern provinces.
There is no mistaking those characteristics.
それだけ特徴があれば
見間違えたりはしない
君は 腸狩りだね？
You must be the Bowel Hunter.
What kind of evil nickname is that?
（スバル）
何だ その超物騒な名前
It's derived from her unique style of killing.
その殺し方の特徴的なところから
付いた異名だよ
Her name is known across the capital
as that of a dangerous individual.
危険人物として
王都でも名前が挙がっている
ラインハルト
そう 騎士の中の騎士―
Reinhard...
Yes, a knight among knights,
born as the Sword Saint, correct?
剣聖の家系ね
How delightful. I have so many fun opponents.
すごいわ
こんなに楽しい相手ばかりだなんて
There are quite a few things I'd like to ask you.
（ラインハルト）
いろいろと 聞きたいこともある
投降をお勧めしますが
I strongly suggest you surrender.
You expect a starving predator
to resist such choice, juicy prey?
血の滴る極上の獲物を前にして
飢えた肉食獣が我慢するとでも？
Subaru, stand back a bit.
スバル 少し離れていて
If you could stay next to her, I'd appreciate it.
あの方のそばにいてくれると助かる
You got it.
合点承知
バケモノみてえな女だから
油断しないでな
That woman is basically a monster,
so don't let your guard down.
As luck would have it,
幸いなことに―
怪物狩りは
僕の専売特許でもあるんだ
hunting monsters happens to be my specialty.
Old Man Rom is still alive?
ロム爺 生きてたのか
He isn't out of the woods yet.
I have to heal him now.
まだ安心はできない
すぐに治療しないと
いいのか？
You really want to?
He's part of the gang that stole your insignia.
この爺さん お前の徽章を
盗んだ一味だぜ
だからよ
That's why.
He'll repay me with information after he recovers.
無事に治ってもらって―
その恩を逆手に
情報を聞き出すの
He wouldn't lie to the person who saved his life.
命の恩人相手なら
ウソなんて きっとつかないわ
I'm doing this for myself as much as him.
これも私のための行為よ
I would rather not use violence on a woman.
女性相手に
あまり乱暴はしたくないんですが
The rumors are true.
（エルザ）
ウワサどおり いえ―
No...
ウワサ以上の存在なのね あなたは
You are even better than they suggest.
I'm not sure I'll live up to your expectations.
ご期待に添えるかどうか
Aren't you going to use that sword at your hip?
その腰の剣は使わないのかしら
I would love to experience
its legendary sharpness.
伝説の切れ味
味わってみたいのだけど
（ラインハルト）
この剣は 抜くべき時以外は
抜けないようになっている
This sword can only be drawn when needed.
The fact that it hasn't left its sheath
鞘(さや)から刀身が出ていない
ということは―
means this is not one of those times.
その時ではないということです
安く見られてしまったものだわ
I do believe I've been underestimated.
（ラインハルト）
僕 個人としては
困らされる判断ですよ
Well, it's an upsetting judgment for me as well.
ですから
こちらで相手させてもらいます
Therefore,
I shall take you on with this instead.
ご不満ですか？
Do you object?
No, it is wonderful.
いいえ ステキ
Very wonderful!
ステキだわ
楽しませてちょうだいね
Please, do entertain me.
Now you've lost your weapon,
I strongly suggest you surrender.
武器を失ったのなら
投降をお勧めします
She's got a second one, Reinhard!
２本目があるぞ ラインハルト！
I'm impressed you knew.
よく分かったわね
I learned the hard way.
実体験があったんでな
But I don't have merely two fangs.
ただし 牙は２本だけではないの
Would you mind if we start again?
仕切り直しに
つきあって頂ける？
Would you be satisfied if I were
to divest you of all your weapons?
（ラインハルト）
全ての武器を切り落とせば
満足してもらえるかな
If I lose my fangs, I'll use my claws.
（エルザ）
牙がなくなれば 爪で―
爪がなくなれば 骨で
骨がなくなれば 命で―
If I lose my claws, I'll use my bones.
And if I lose my bones, I'll use my very life.
That's how the Bowel Hunter fights.
それが 腸狩りのやり方よ
Reinhard won't fail to land
the decisive blow, will he?
（スバル）
まさか ラインハルトですら―
決め手に欠けるってんじゃ
ねえだろうな
He can't fight at full strength
because I'm using my spirit arts.
私が精霊術を使ってるから
彼は本気が出せないの
どういう因果関係？
How are those things related?
If Reinhard were truly intent on fighting,
ラインハルトが
本当に戦うつもりになれば―
all the mana in the atmosphere
would turn away from me.
大気中のマナは
私にそっぽ向くもの
I'm almost done healing him.
そろそろ治療が終わる
合図したら 彼に声をかけて
When I give the signal, let him know.
もう大丈夫　お願い
He's all right now. Go ahead.
ラインハルト
よく分からんが やっちまえ！
Reinhard! I don't really get it, but do your thing!
（エルザ）
何を見せてくれるの？
What will you show me?
The swordplay of the Astrea family.
（ラインハルト）
アストレア家の剣げきを
Elsa Granhiert, the Bowel Hunter.
腸狩り エルザ･グランヒルテ
Reinhard van Astrea, the Sword Saint.
剣聖の家系 ラインハルト･
ヴァン･アストレア
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
（スバル）
おい おい おいー！
何が 怪物狩りは自分の領分だ
Hunting monsters is your specialty, my ass!
You're a monster yourself!
お前のほうが
十分 バケモノじゃねえか
Even I'm a bit hurt by comments like that, Subaru.
そう言われると
さすがに僕も傷つくよ スバル
I'm sorry I pushed you so hard.
無理をさせてしまったね
ゆっくりおやすみ
Rest well now.
There isn't a shadow left, let alone a body.
（スバル）
死体どころか 影も残ってねえ
This is all that's left after a single swing?
これが
剣 振っただけの現場か？
無事に終わったの？
Is it over now?
Yeah.
おっ おお…
ホントの意味で どうにかな
I have no idea how, but I guess so.
Why are you staring at me? That's quite rude.
ジロジロと どうしたの？
すごーく失礼だと思うけど
It's just that your arms, legs,
and even your head are still attached.
（スバル）
いや 手足はもちろん
首もちゃんとついてるよな
Of course they are. Don't say such scary things.
（サテラ）
当たり前でしょ
怖いこと言わないでくれる？
Yeah, you're right. Why wouldn't they be?
（スバル）
そうだな 当たり前だよな
もちろん俺の手もついてるし―
I still have my arms too.
And there's no knife in my back
or gaping hole in my gut.
背中にナイフが
生えてもいなけりゃ―
腹に でかい風穴が
空いてたりもしないぜ
You talk as if you've
experienced those things before.
生えてたり 空いてたりした時期が
あるみたいな言い方するわね
There was a time when I did.
そんな時期もあったけどな
Oh, yeah, Reinhard. I haven't thanked you yet.
そういやラインハルト
まだ礼 言ってなかった
You saved my ass!
マジ 助かった
Back in the alley too.
さっきの路地のことといい―
I guess you heard my heart's cries
for help, my dear friend!
俺の心の叫びが
聞こえたのかよ 友よ
I'd certainly be proud if I did,
それができたなら
僕も胸を張るんだけどね
友達くん
my friend.
While desperately running around the streets,
彼女が 必死で路地を
走り回っていたんだ
your companion over there ran into me
and asked for my help.
そして僕に助けを求めた
あの子は…
She's...
Now hang on...
待った 待った
We'd be a pile of guts right now
if she hadn't brought Reinhard.
あいつがラインハルト
呼んでくんなきゃ―
俺たちは全滅してたんだぜ
ここは俺の顔に免じて
氷の彫像の刑は見送ってくれよ
Take a good look at my face and rethink
the ice-statue punishment, okay?
I wouldn't do something so violent!
そんな乱暴しないわよ
というか
あなたの顔に免じてって…
And what does your face have to do with—
ハッ スバル！
Subaru!
She'll go for the gut!
（スバル）狙いは―
腹！
この子は またジャマを
That boy got in my way yet again.
That's enough, Elsa!
（ラインハルト）
そこまでだ エルザ
Soon enough, I'll disembowel everyone here.
いずれ この場にいる全員の腹を
切り開いてあげる
Till then, take good care of your bowels.
それまでは せいぜい
腸をかわいがっておいて
Are you unharmed?
ご無事ですか
My well-being isn't the issue right now!
私のことは どうでもいいでしょう
それより―
More importantly,
are you all right?
ちょっと大丈夫？
ムチャしすぎよ
That was far too reckless!
お… 楽勝 楽勝
It was nothing. Really.
It was a long, hard road,
but I finally got this far.
随分と遠回りしちまった けど
やっとここまで たどり着いた
My name is Natsuki Subaru!
俺の名前はナツキ･スバル
俺ってば 今 まさに
君を狂人から守りぬいた 命の恩人
And I just saved your life from a heinous villain!
Are we OK on that?
ここまでＯＫ？
"OK"?
ＯＫ…
It means "Are we clear on that?" So...
（スバル）
よろしいですか の意
ってなわけで―
OK?
ＯＫ？
O-OK...
おっ ＯＫ…
I'm the hero who saved your life!
命の恩人 レスキュー俺
そして それに
助けられたヒロインが君
And you are the heroine I saved!
So wouldn't that mean you should
repay me in kind? Wouldn't it?
そんなら 相応の礼があっても
いいんじゃないかないかな！
All right, I get it.
分かってるわよ
Only if it's within my power, of course.
私にできることならって
条件付きだけど
In that case, I have only one request!
（スバル）
なら 俺の願いはオンリーワン
１個だけだ
And my request is...
そう 俺の願いは―
Please tell me your name.
君の名前を教えてほしい
ウッフフフ　エミリア
Emilia.
Huh?
My name is Emilia. Just Emilia.
私の名前はエミリア
ただのエミリアよ
Thank you, Subaru.
ありがとう スバル
Thank you for saving me.
私を助けてくれて
For all the injuries I got, all the crying I did,
（スバル）
あれだけ傷ついて
あれだけ嘆いて
all the pain I felt, and all the fighting
with my life on the line...
あれだけ痛い思いをして
あれだけ命がけで戦い抜いて―
その報酬が
彼女の名前と笑顔がひとつ
My only rewards were her name and a single smile.
ハア 全く―
Jeez...
Talk about unequal compensation.
割に合わねえ
Anyway, Subaru, I'm impressed that you're unhurt.
（ラインハルト）
それにしても スバル
よく無事だったね
I blocked with that thing at just the right time.
（スバル）
そいつで
とっさにガードしたかんな
If not for that, I'd be in two pieces right now.
それがなきゃ 今頃は
胴体真っ二つだ
True, if not for this...
（ラインハルト）
そうだね これがなければ…
Huh?
あれ？
（スバル）
ヤバイ これ俺にも先が読めた
Uh-oh.
I should have seen this coming.
（エミリア）スバル？
Subaru?
Subaru!
スバル！
Man...
（スバル）
ああ… 焦ったりしてても
マジかわいいな
She's so cute even when she's panicking.
A fantasy world...
異世界ファンタジー…
There. His treatment is complete.
（エミリア）
よし 治療は完了
どうにか峠は越えたでしょう
He should be out of danger now.
By the way, Emilia-sama,
what is your relation to Subaru?
（ラインハルト）
ところで エミリア様―
彼 スバルとは
どういうご関係ですか？
A passing acquaintance?
（エミリア）行きずり？
I don't recall coming across him before today.
今まで スバルと会った
覚えはないわ
ここで―
As far as I know, we met for
the first time earlier today.
ついさっき会ったのが
初めてのはずなんだけど
But he was searching for you.
ですが 彼は
あなたを捜していました
He said he had something to give you.
渡したい物があると
That's what makes it so strange.
だから不思議なのよね
彼の身柄はどうしましょうか？
What shall we do with him?
I would be glad to take him home as a guest.
よろしければ 当家のほうで
客人として扱いますが
No, I'll take him home with me.
ううん こっちで連れ帰ります
That way, I can learn what's really going on.
そのほうが事情もはっきりするし
But more importantly,
それよりも―
what will become of that girl and the old man?
あの女の子や
お爺さんはどうなるの？
Officially, I cannot overlook what they've done.
（ラインハルト）
職務上 見逃すことはできない
部類であると考えます
But...
ですが―
あいにく自分は
今日は非番でして
Unfortunately, I'm off duty today.
フッ 悪い騎士様ね
What a bad knight.
Is this old man your family?
そのお爺さんは
あなたの家族？
Something like that.
そうみたいなもんだ
Old Man Rom is all I have.
ロム爺は私にとって
たった１人… うん―
じいちゃんみてえなもんだな
I guess he's like my grandpa.
I see. I only have one family member too.
そう
私の家族も１人だけ
He's always asleep when it matters most, though.
肝心な時に 眠りこけてるし―
起きてる時には
絶対にそんなことは言えないけど
Not that I'd ever say that when he's awake.
I thought you'd be a lot harsher on me.
もっと すげえ
きつくくるかと思ってた ごめん
I'm sorry.
命を助けてもらったんだ―
You saved my life,
and I can't let a debt go unpaid.
恩知らずなマネは
できねえ
I'll return what I stole.
盗ったもんは返す
大事なもんなら―
If it's that important, keep it hidden,
今度から
盗られねえように―
so it won't get stolen again.
ちゃんと隠せよ
It feels funny hearing that from you.
（エミリア）
あなたに その忠告
されるのって―
ヘンテコな気分ね
Reinhard?
ラインハルト？
You're hurting me! Let go!
痛いっつうの　放せ
なんてことだ
How can this be?
What is your name?
君の名前は？
I-It's Felt, why?
フェルトだ
And your family name? How old are you?
家名は？ 年齢はいくつだい？
I don't have anything fancy like a family name!
家名なんて大層なもんは
持っちゃいねえよ
I'm... about fifteen, I think.
年は たぶん15ぐらい
I don't know my birthday.
誕生日が分からねえから
つか 放せよ！
Look, just let me go!
エミリア様 先ほどのお約束は
守れなくなりました
Emilia-sama, I am afraid
I cannot keep my promise to you.
I shall be taking this girl with me.
彼女の身柄は
自分が預からせて頂きます
May I ask why?
理由を聞いても？
徽章盗難での罰というなら…
If it's for stealing my insignia...
Indeed, that is no small crime.
それも 決して
小さくない罪ですが―
But compared to the gravity of overlooking
the crime unfolding before me, it's trivial.
今 こうして目の前の光景を―
見過ごすことの
罪深さと比べれば―
ささいなことにすぎません
I need you to come with me.
ついてきてもらいたい
すまないが 拒否権は与えられない
I'm sorry, but I cannot allow you to refuse.
Get over yourself!
ふざけ… 助けたからって
あんま調子に乗んな！
Just because you helped me, doesn't mean—
また 騎士様らしくないやり方
That wasn't very courtly either.
加減は心得ております
I was careful not to use too much.
Emilia-sama, you will likely be called upon soon.
エミリア様 また近いうちに
呼び出しがあるかと思われます
ご理解を
I hope you understand.
Please take good care of Subaru.
スバルのことを
どうかよろしくお願いします
落ち着いて月を見られるのは―
Today may be the last chance we
have to gaze calmly at the moon.
今日が最後かもしれないな
Starting Life from   Zero
in a   Different World